prospectmagazine.co.uk 2019-05-31

# Prospect Privacy & Cookie Policy | Prospect Magazine

**Prospect Privacy & Cookie Policy**

_Prospect_  Publishing Limited (“ **Prospect** ”, “ **We** ”, “ **Us** ” or “ **Our** ”) recognises the importance of protecting your personal information is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data,  it also describes our practices around cookies and tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

  1. **_IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE_**
  2. **_THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU_**
  3. **_HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED_**
  4. **_HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA_**
  5. **_DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA_**
  6. **_INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS_**
  7. **_DATA SECURITY_**
  8. **_DATA RETENTION_**
  9. **_YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS_**
  10. **_GLOSSARY_**
  11. **IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**

**PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Prospect collects and processes your personal data, including any data you may provide through filling in forms on www.prospectmagazine.co.uk ( **our site** ) or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our newsletter or events, take out a subscription, place an order on our site, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on our site, enter a competition, promotion or survey, via cookies and when you report a problem with our site. It describes our general privacy practices that apply to personal information we collect, use and share about subscribers and other individuals, within our business partners, suppliers and other organisations with which Prospect has or contemplates a business relationship with.

Our site is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

**CONTROLLER**

Prospect Publishing Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data.

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise _your legal rights_ , please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below.

**CONTACT DETAILS**

Our full details are:

Full name of legal entity: Prospect Publishing Limited

Email address:  publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk

Postal address: 2 Queen Anne’s Gate, London, SW1H 9AA

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([ _www.ico.org.uk_](http://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**

This version was last updated on 10 May 2018.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us by contacting: publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk.

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

  2. **THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details.
  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of subscriptions you have purchased from us or events you have registered for with us.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our newsletters, website and subscription. **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract, including any subscription contract,  we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with your subscription or event ticket details). In this case, we may have to cancel a subscription or event registration you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

  3. **HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
  * sign up for our newsletter;
  * subscribe to our magazine;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
  * Technical Data from

analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU

  * Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of subscription marketing services based inside the EU.
  * Publicly available information on you derived from social media integrated with our site.

  4. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. Including but not limited

to providing you with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous transaction or negotiation with you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Click to find out more about the types of lawful basis that we will rely on to process your personal data, see the  _lawful basis column  _in the table below.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw such consent to marketing at any time by contacting publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To process and deliver your subscription including: 

(a) register you as a new subscriber

(b) manage payments

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Transaction

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you   
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products)  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw or competition  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences  | (a) Technical 

(b) Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about offers that may be of interest to you  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)   
  
**MARKETING**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.

**PROMOTIONAL OFFERS FROM US**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which events or offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have subscribed for our magazine or newsletter or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**THIRD-PARTY MARKETING**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company other than Prospect for marketing purposes.

**OPTING OUT**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by _Contacting us_ at any time at publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a subscription or other transaction.

**COOKIES**

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the web server to collect information from the browser. Find out more about the use of cookies on [http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/). Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website and may track your usage. This helps us to provide you with a better experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. Most browsers allow you to turn off all or some browser cookies. To do this look at the “help” menu on your browser. Switching off cookies may restrict your use of the website and/or delay or affect the way in which it operates. If you continue without changing your settings, we’ll assume that you are happy to receive all the cookies on the website.

The purposes for which we use cookies include:

**Purpose** | **Explanation**  
---|---  
Processes | Intended to make the website work in the way you expect. For example, we use a cookie that tells us whether you have already signed up for an account.  
Authentication, Security, and Compliance | Intended to prevent fraud, protect your data from unauthorized parties, and comply with legal requirements. For example, we use cookies to determine if you are logged in.  
Preferences | Intended to remember information about how you prefer the website to behave and look. For example, we use a cookie that tells us whether you have declined to allow us to use your phone’s geolocation data.  
Notifications | Intended to allow or prevent notices of information or options that we think could improve your use of the website. For example, we use a cookie that stops us from showing you the signup notification if you have already seen it.  
Advertising | Intended to make advertising more relevant to users and more valuable to advertisers. For example, we may use cookies to serve you interest-based ads, such as ads that are displayed to you based on your visits to other websites, or to tell us if you have recently clicked on an ad.  
Analytics | Intended to help us understand how visitors use the website. For example, we use a cookie that tells us how our search suggestions correlate to your interactions with the search page. We use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. We use the data provided by this web analytics service to develop our site content around our users’ interests. You can opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics through [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/) or by downloading and installing the _[Google Analytics Opt-out Browser](https://emea01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Ftools.google.com%2Fdlpage%2Fgaoptout%3Fhl%3Den&data=02%7C01%7Cbukunola.alakija%40resolution.co.uk%7Cff41216e359e46b34f4808d4b1786ffe%7C0bbfcf87e6044790969f3eec674cdbe9%7C0%7C0%7C636328578230012091&sdata=xb3RzOVqaY%2BAOG3clgQ99dlEwY6hYOumf1pOTURSgc0%3D&reserved=0) _[Add-on](https://emea01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Ftools.google.com%2Fdlpage%2Fgaoptout%3Fhl%3Den&data=02%7C01%7Cbukunola.alakija%40resolution.co.uk%7Cff41216e359e46b34f4808d4b1786ffe%7C0bbfcf87e6044790969f3eec674cdbe9%7C0%7C0%7C636328578230012091&sdata=xb3RzOVqaY%2BAOG3clgQ99dlEwY6hYOumf1pOTURSgc0%3D&reserved=0)  
  
**CHANGE OF PURPOSE**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please _contact us at_ publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

  5. **DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

  * Third Parties as set out in the _Glossary_.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
  * As required by law, or if in good faith we believe disclosure is required by law.

We never sell personal information or pass it to third parties for marketing purposes without your permission. We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

  6. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** “). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [_European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries_](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see [_European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield_](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please contact publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

  7. **DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site.

  8. **DATA RETENTION**

**HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see _Request erasure_  below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

  9. **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please click on the links below to find out more about these rights:

  * _Request access to your personal data_.
  * _Request correction of your personal data_.
  * _Request erasure of your personal data_.
  * _Object to processing of your personal data_.
  * _Request restriction of processing your personal data_.
  * _Request transfer of your personal data_.
  * _Right to withdraw consent_.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please _Contact us at publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk._

**NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

  10. **GLOSSARY**

**LAWFUL BASIS**

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by _Contacting us at publishing@prospectmagazine.co.uk._

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

**THIRD PARTIES**

  * Service providers acting as processors, who provide subscription management, mail management, IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the United Kingdom who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
  * We may share your personal data with Audit Bureau of Circulation Ltd, a third-party auditing organization, so they can verify statistics about circulation and usage of our magazine or review our policies, processes and procedures for compliance with relevant standards. You can view their privacy policy here: www.abc.org.uk/privacy-policy

**YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
